# **Pavel Kirilin**

Software Developer / Moscow, Russia / https://pkirilin.github.io

Email: kirilin.pav@gmail.com / LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pkirilin / GitHub: https://github.com/pkirilin

## **Summary**

Software developer with 4+ years of experience mainly on the .NET stack and knowledge of modern frontend technologies (React, Angular). For the last couple of years have been developing integration REST APIs based on cloud solutions (Microsoft Azure). Also developed small APIs and scripts using Node.js.

# Skills

C# | .NET 6 | ASP.NET Core | Entity Framework Core | MySQL | PostgreSQL | Docker HTML | CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Redux | Node.js | ExpressJS

# **Experience**

Dodo Brands / https://dodobrands.io / Moscow, Russia

An international foodservice franchise, which has brands located in over 16 countries around the world.

## Developer (Jan 2021 - Present)

- Expanded the company's information system capabilities for integration with third-party services by designing, documenting, and developing 6 public API endpoints for external developers.
- implemented the MVP of the Dodo IS Marketplace service with the functionality of viewing and managing all external integrations connected to the system solely in 3 months.
- Automated the gathering of the technical support team metrics from 2 third-party SaaS services by developing an
  operational metrics dashboard for the 2nd line team, which saved 2-3 days of manual work per week during the
  year.
- Increased the efficiency and the SLA of the technical support team by 8% during the year by developing a support bot for automating the team's daily operations.

#### Super Brands / Moscow, Russia

A distributor of more than 12 world brands of clothing, footwear, and accessories for over 15 retailers in Russia.

#### **.NET developer** (Jul 2019 - Oct 2020)

- Provided technical support to the brand management team of 5-8 people and fixed several bugs based on their feedback.
- Increased the performance of sending orders to the internal accounting system by changing the existing integration from SOAP to REST.
- Improved the algorithms for importing and exporting products in Excel format by making search and navigation in export files easier.

#### Quorum / Moscow, Russia

An integrator with 20 years of experience providing IT solutions for over 40 financial institutions in Russia.

## .NET developer (Nov 2018 - Jun 2019)

• Developed the application for automating banking loan pipeline

#### Education

**Bauman Moscow State Technical University /** <a href="https://www.bmstu.ru">https://www.bmstu.ru</a> / Moscow, Russia BASc, Informatics and Computer Science (Sep 2014 - Jun 2018) Robotics and Complex Automation, Computer-Aided Design and Engineering.

### Additional information

- Languages: Russian (native), English (upper-Intermediate)
- Citizenship: Russian Federation